<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>brianbruff</author>
  <title>Typescript Gang of 4 Series</title>
  <description />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;When I started out writing this blog way back circa 2008 timeframe it was fully focused on .NET tech, things have changed with time and while .NET is still my second love (my first love was C++) I now find myself in a multiple of different language frameworks and tech. I also find that I’m not so much on bleeding edge but rather focus my efforts where I expect I’ll get most rewards. I stayed away from ASP5 until about now-ish i.e when the RC1 version is out in the wild and given so much has changed I’m glad I did.&amp;#160; &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;A few years back I heard of this language coming out of MS called Typescript, it seemed like a great idea but I didn’t immediately jump on the bandwagon, fast forward a few years to the middle of last summer where I found myself making some architectural decisions, one of which was typescript vs bable vs other transpilers. In the end my head told me Typescript even though my heart favoured JavaScript, now fast forward 6ish months to now and I can honestly say this was one of the best decisions I ever made.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;So now I’d like to share the love as such and re created the Gang of four patterns in typescript over a series of blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;h2&gt;Gang of four&lt;/h2&gt;  &lt;p&gt;So what is gang of four I hear you ask! Well basically it’s a set of patterns outlined in a software engineering book written by four people (Gof gang of four) which describes solutions to common problems in software design, the book includes examples in C++ and Smalltalk. My posts will attempt to reproduce same said patterns in Typescript.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I’ll update this article as I add to this blog post series, the patterns I’ll be covering are:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;h3&gt;Creational&lt;/h3&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Abstract factory&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Builder&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Factory&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Prototype&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Singleton&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;h3&gt;Structural&lt;/h3&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Adapter&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Bridge&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Composite&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Decorator&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Facade&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Flyweight&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Proxy&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;h3&gt;Behavioral&lt;/h3&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Chain of responsibility&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Command&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Interpreter&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Iterator&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Mediator&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Memento&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Observer&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;State&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Strategy&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Template method&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h4&gt;Visitor&lt;/h4&gt;  &lt;h2&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/h2&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I’ll create all these patterns on Github &lt;a href="https://github.com/brianbruff/GofTs" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; so if anyone wants to help me out please do!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>False</ispublished>
  <isdeleted>False</isdeleted>
  <iscommentsenabled>True</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2015-12-09 15:05:42</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-12-09 15:05:42</lastModified>
  <raters>0</raters>
  <rating>0</rating>
  <slug>Typescript-Gang-of-4-Series</slug>
  <tags />
  <comments />
  <categories />
  <notifications />
</post>