<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>Admin</author>
  <title>Tech of the week</title>
  <description>Appears to be the story of my life lately, just as I get excited and proficient on one stack I get s</description>
  <content>&lt;p&gt;Appears to be the story of my life lately, just as I get excited and proficient on one stack I get side tracked with something else. The latest stack I&amp;rsquo;m playing with is the Ionic2 framework, but first some history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;UX Stacks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written UX applications in many different way in the past&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;java swing (albeit i&amp;rsquo;d never put this on my resume as I can&amp;rsquo;t recall a single bit of that application i helped a student friend with so many years ago)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MFC &amp;ndash; Oh the pain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ATL/WTL &amp;ndash; Actually i quite like this back in the old C++ days when men were men.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C# Windows forms &amp;ndash; Spent years on this stack and if you&amp;rsquo;re happy with battleship grey it&amp;rsquo;s still quite RAD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WPF/Silverlight &amp;ndash; Wrote quite a few applications in this, probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t call myself an expert but I can xaml like the next guy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MVC3+ &amp;ndash; Have written and still support a quite a few MVC applications it was the bridge that finally moved me heavily to web client side tech.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objective-C/XCode &amp;ndash; A handful of iPhone applications, it&amp;rsquo;s ok, language is a little weird yes but use it for a week read a few books/material and you&amp;rsquo;ll make a good stab at it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xamarin &amp;ndash; A nice approach for writing mobile apps in&amp;nbsp; c#, problem is you still need to use the native designers (yes i know about xamarin forms.. are we really going to talk about that?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web tech, My transition to the web was a natural progression that leveraged things I&amp;rsquo;d learned with other frameworks, e.g Knockout was familiar from wpf data binding, angular has somewhat a familiarity to MVC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Ionic2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is Ionic2? In short it&amp;rsquo;s a framework for writing mobile (and progressive) apps. As you&amp;rsquo;ve seen above I&amp;rsquo;ve already ways of writing mobile apps, So why something new? Why not! in this world &amp;ndash; always be learning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case there were some more compelling reasons,&amp;nbsp; see for the last year I was an architect and hands on developer for a new web application using angularjs v1 sass, typescript and a tonne of wonderful libraries. Ionic2 is built around the same stacks, applications use angular2, html5, typescript, saas, gulp etc, the list goes on and on. Apparently I&amp;rsquo;m finding my home in this world, in fact if i was to write a greenfield desktop application I&amp;rsquo;d seriously consider writing it with html tech and framing with Atom/Electron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sample app&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table border="0" width="619" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="2"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="400"&gt;&lt;a href="/image.axd?picture=image_thumb2_1.png"&gt;&lt;img style="margin: 0px 10px 0px 0px; border: 0px currentcolor; padding-top: 0px; padding-right: 0px; padding-left: 0px; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="image_thumb2" src="/image.axd?picture=image_thumb2_thumb_1.png" alt="image_thumb2" width="414" height="640" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td valign="top" width="417"&gt;Taking the application on the left as an example, &lt;br /&gt;I was to create this screen in a few hours, sure i&amp;rsquo;s not the prettiest and contrasts are high, but the point is that from a blank canvas it only took a few hours to design and implement this screen using Ionic2 and web technologies. I&amp;rsquo;m a little spoiled as I can somewhat ignore the stubborn elephant in the room *CSS*. i&amp;rsquo;m targeting the latest devices so I&amp;rsquo;m getting to use flexbox for layout , css3 transitions etc. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m seriously convinced that when it comes to writing general purpose mobile applications Ionic2 will be hard to beat. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;I know if i was to write the same screen in xcode/android studio it would take me a lot longer to implement this design. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Check out Ionic2 for yourself you won&amp;rsquo;t regret it.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <isdeleted>False</isdeleted>
  <iscommentsenabled>True</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2015-01-01 00:00:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2021-10-20 10:09:27</lastModified>
  <raters>0</raters>
  <rating>0</rating>
  <slug>Tech-of-the-week</slug>
  <tags />
  <comments />
  <categories />
  <notifications />
</post>