<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>brianbruff</author>
  <title>The future is live</title>
  <description />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Probably like a lot of other computer people I find myself working with more than one computer. There in lies the problem, is it worth the overhead of manually having to synchronize all these pcs?&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Sure source code is and always has been handled by a source control repository, tfs/svn etc. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;But what about documents; during the week I started setting up a new desktop machine, tonight while working on a java project (i know i know) i found that i needed to copy a few strings into the clipboard as I was developing, now I usually do this from within vs2010 but I’m not sure how to do this from the Java Netbeans IDE so i though I’d use MS Onenote.. there in lied the problem. I wanted to access the notebook I had on my laptop but I didn’t want to start an import/export process (so 90ies &lt;img style="border-bottom-style: none; border-right-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-left-style: none" class="wlEmoticon wlEmoticon-rollingonthefloorlaughing" alt="Rolling on the floor laughing" src="/blog/image.axd?picture=wlEmoticon-rollingonthefloorlaughing.png" /&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Turns out that onenote 2010 allows me to save my notebook on a network share (not so exciting because i could do this with UNC paths); but moreover it allows you to keep your notebook synchronized with windows live office space.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;So now I‘ve got my notebooks sitting in the cloud and cached and accessed locally on different computers. Now I’ve not really invested much if any time in could services, but I think it’s time to start, I’ve a sneaky suspicion that going forward operating systems will become more and more cloud integrated. I can’t see anyone choosing to manually upload and download documents to servers when this can now easily be managed by hitting that save button.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <isdeleted>False</isdeleted>
  <iscommentsenabled>True</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2011-01-16 21:57:29</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-07-09 11:11:33</lastModified>
  <raters>0</raters>
  <rating>0</rating>
  <slug>The-future-is-live</slug>
  <tags />
  <comments />
  <categories />
  <notifications>
    <email>b@briankeating.net</email>
  </notifications>
</post>