<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>brianbruff</author>
  <title>The Ultimate Top 25 Chuck Norris “The Programmer” Jokes.</title>
  <description />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;1. When Chuck Norris throws exceptions, it’s across the room.   &lt;br /&gt;2. All arrays Chuck Norris declares are of infinite size, because Chuck Norris knows no bounds.    &lt;br /&gt;3. Chuck Norris doesn’t have disk latency because the hard drive knows to hurry the hell up.    &lt;br /&gt;4. Chuck Norris writes code that optimizes itself.    &lt;br /&gt;5. Chuck Norris can’t test for equality because he has no equal.    &lt;br /&gt;6. Chuck Norris doesn’t need garbage collection because he doesn’t call .Dispose(), he calls .DropKick().    &lt;br /&gt;7. Chuck Norris’s first program was kill -9.    &lt;br /&gt;8. Chuck Norris burst the dot com bubble.    &lt;br /&gt;9. All browsers support the hex definitions #chuck and #norris for the colors black and blue.    &lt;br /&gt;10. MySpace actually isn’t your space, it’s Chuck’s (he just lets you use it).    &lt;br /&gt;11. Chuck Norris can write infinite recursion functions…and have them return.    &lt;br /&gt;12. Chuck Norris can solve the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tower_of_Hanoi"&gt;&lt;font color="#0066cc"&gt;Towers of Hanoi&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in one move.    &lt;br /&gt;13. The only pattern Chuck Norris knows is God Object.    &lt;br /&gt;14. Chuck Norris finished World of Warcraft.    &lt;br /&gt;15. Project managers never ask Chuck Norris for estimations…ever.    &lt;br /&gt;16. Chuck Norris doesn’t use web standards as the web will conform to him.    &lt;br /&gt;17. “It works on my machine” always holds true for Chuck Norris.    &lt;br /&gt;18. Whiteboards are white because Chuck Norris scared them that way.    &lt;br /&gt;19. Chuck Norris doesn’t do &lt;a href="http://www.codesqueeze.com/the-burn-down-charts/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0066cc"&gt;Burn Down charts&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, he does Smack Down charts.    &lt;br /&gt;20. Chuck Norris can delete the Recycling Bin.    &lt;br /&gt;21. Chuck Norris’s beard can type 140 wpm.    &lt;br /&gt;22. Chuck Norris can unit test entire applications with a single assert.    &lt;br /&gt;23. Chuck Norris doesn’t bug hunt as that signifies a probability of failure, he goes bug killing.    &lt;br /&gt;24. Chuck Norris’s keyboard doesn’t have a Ctrl key because nothing controls Chuck Norris.    &lt;br /&gt;25. When Chuck Norris is web surfing websites get the message “Warning: Internet Explorer has deemed this user to be malicious or dangerous. Proceed?”. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <isdeleted>False</isdeleted>
  <iscommentsenabled>True</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2011-06-05 12:12:57</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-07-09 11:10:34</lastModified>
  <raters>0</raters>
  <rating>0</rating>
  <slug>The-Ultimate-Top-25-Chuck-Norris-“The-Programmer”-Jokes</slug>
  <tags />
  <comments>
    <comment id="e6feb5f2-7cfb-49de-a090-bf46e87b6e30" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True" spam="False" deleted="False">
      <date>2013-01-19 05:07:12</date>
      <author>Chuck</author>
      <email>tcasting@ymzil.com</email>
      <country>fr</country>
      <ip>109.22.84.181</ip>
      <website>http://6buzz.com/01/02/top-17-des-phrases-et-des-citations-de-chuck-norris/</website>
      <moderatedby>brianbruff</moderatedby>
      <avatar />
      <content>lol in my country (France) Not more citation on Chuck Norris so thank you (im sorry for my bad english) :D its very funny </content>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <categories />
  <notifications />
</post>