<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>brianbruff</author>
  <title>AWS or AZURE</title>
  <description />
  <content>&lt;h2&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;  &lt;p&gt;So way back circa 2008 I registered for AWS free tier, now back then I was working in a different industry that didn’t have much need for ‘the cloud’ I played with a few linux vm’s during that year but nothing came of it and my trial expired.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Fast forward two years and Azure was born at least in public,, I was immediately sold and was all-in. I’ve used abused and consulted on more Azure projects than I can remember and anytime the subject of AWS came up I dismissed it as a inferior pioneer on cloud tech, I mean just look at the console it’s offending to the eye is it not?&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Fast forward another two years and I found myself while heavily swallowing the PAAS cool-aid recommending AWS over Azure to a client, why? Simply because AWS have a managed offering for Oracle and that particular client did not have the knowledge or appetite to manage their own oracle server.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;This did open my eye that there might be a bit more to AWS than an ugly console, an opportunity presented itself to become AWS certified and I jumped at it, now as I write this article I can put this lovely logo &lt;a href="./image.axd?picture=Solutions-Architect-Associate.png"&gt;&lt;img title="Solutions-Architect-Associate" style="border-left-width: 0px; border-right-width: 0px; background-image: none; border-bottom-width: 0px; padding-top: 0px; padding-left: 0px; margin: 0px 10px 0px 0px; display: inline; padding-right: 0px; border-top-width: 0px" border="0" alt="Solutions-Architect-Associate" src="./image.axd?picture=Solutions-Architect-Associate_thumb.png" width="244" height="102" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;on my business card.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;h2&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/h2&gt;  &lt;h2&gt;Learning’s&lt;/h2&gt;  &lt;p&gt;So what have I learned about AWS in in my quest for certification? Well the console is not nearly as offending as I once believed it to be, in fact I think it’s more practical than that sexy looking new Azure portal, it’s faster to get things done in than constantly sliding those Azure portal blades around the place that’s for sure. As for feature parity, for the most part both platforms tend to support the same features in the general sense but once you drill down differences do start to emerge. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I’ve also decided it about high time that I also get certified in Azure, (underway), this should give me the street cred I need for what I’m going to try achieve and hopefully my findings be as impartial as possible.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;h2&gt;Cloud Wars&lt;/h2&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Starting from my next blog post I’m going to start comparing features on both platforms and outline the pros and cons of each… Stay tuned to what should be a very interesting blog series. Obviously the topics are vast, so, if anyone has any requests please send me an email: b at briankeating.net.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <isdeleted>False</isdeleted>
  <iscommentsenabled>True</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2016-01-17 22:23:11</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2016-04-01 10:34:36</lastModified>
  <raters>0</raters>
  <rating>0</rating>
  <slug>AWS-or-AZURE</slug>
  <tags>
    <tag>CloudWars</tag>
    <tag>introduction</tag>
  </tags>
  <comments />
  <categories>
    <category>05dd30fa-4cf5-4938-897f-33c8bd526a66</category>
    <category>0d55a24e-db67-40a3-af5b-1a77c336bece</category>
    <category>d874ce79-a2c3-4422-b687-9f2e4d82273e</category>
  </categories>
  <notifications />
</post>
