<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>brianbruff</author>
  <title>It’s COM Jim, but not as we know it!</title>
  <description />
  <content>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Those of you that started out in windows c++ like me are likely familiar with COM&lt;img style="border-bottom-style: none; border-left-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-right-style: none" class="wlEmoticon wlEmoticon-punch" alt="Punch" src="./image.axd?picture=wlEmoticon-punch.png" /&gt;, COM+&lt;img style="border-bottom-style: none; border-left-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-right-style: none" class="wlEmoticon wlEmoticon-ghost" alt="Ghost" src="./image.axd?picture=wlEmoticon-ghost.png" /&gt;, DCOM &lt;img style="border-bottom-style: none; border-left-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-right-style: none" class="wlEmoticon wlEmoticon-ninja" alt="Ninja" src="./image.axd?picture=wlEmoticon-ninja_2.png" /&gt;    &lt;br /&gt;If you stayed in unmanaged land then you’ve probably still very familiar with, ATL, HResults etc.    &lt;br /&gt;However if on the other hand, like me, you progressed into the managed realm, then those icons above probably sum up your recollections.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;For me I once considered myself pretty hot in C++ (shamefully I still do but I’m sure I’d have to spend a week hands on to really tick that box), COM collections on stl (ICollectionOnSTLImpl) were a walk in the park, multiple inheritance was a given and finding you didn’t release a COM reference was the highlight of your day. But, fast forward a few years and then you really scratch your head as to why life had to be so difficult. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Well I’ll answer that question, performance is by far and above one of the biggest factors. With Windows8 fast approaching you may be starting to panic a little, I guess even more so if you started you coding life in a managed kingdom, but fear not, and let me dispel some common misconceptions that are solved with the C++ Component Extensions (C++/CX for short)&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;   &lt;li&gt;COM means HRESULTS – No, C++/CX gives yields exceptions from the underlying Fail HResults.&lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;COM means no returns – No, C++/CX allows return values&lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;COM means reference counting – Kinda, but you don’t have to worry about AddRef and Release, you use the “ref new” keyword and C++/CX does the reference counting for you (not garbage collection!)&lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;COM mens CoCreateInstance etc - Again C++/CX ref new takes care of this for you&lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;COM means interfaces - C++/CX takes care of IUnknow/IDispatch, if fact IDispatch has been superseded.&lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;COM means no inheritance - C++/CX takes care of this for you.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;So will I develop my apps in C++/C#/JS+Html (come on don’t expect me to add VB.NET that battle was lost a long time ago &lt;img style="border-bottom-style: none; border-left-style: none; border-top-style: none; border-right-style: none" class="wlEmoticon wlEmoticon-smile" alt="Smile" src="./image.axd?picture=wlEmoticon-smile_11.png" /&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Well here’s my feelings:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;   &lt;li&gt;C++ maybe, depends on how much pref i need from my machines (sacrificing time to market), if i want to use an existing library,&amp;#160; Parallel patterns library, C++ AMP etc.&lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;C# yes, I like this language and it’s a RAD language (albeit i won’t have access to the full Framework)&lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;JS+HTML, I’m not sold on this yet, maybe, if i want to produce for the web then I choose js+html+asp not silverlight, would I ever have enough of a code base to reuse on WinRT??… jury is out..&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <isdeleted>False</isdeleted>
  <iscommentsenabled>True</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2012-02-21 14:52:23</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2012-02-21 15:23:01</lastModified>
  <raters>1</raters>
  <rating>5</rating>
  <slug>It’s-COM-Jim-but-not-as-we-know-it!</slug>
  <tags />
  <comments />
  <categories />
  <notifications />
</post>